earthday.org 2002-12-07

# Earth Day Network - About Us

Earth Day Network respects your right to privacy. Earth Day Network will only collect Personal Information (defined below) that you voluntarily provide to us and will only disclose it or use it for purposes as disclosed in this Privacy Policy or as disclosed by us at the time information is requested from you. 

****

**Personal Information**

When you visit our website, Earth Day Network does not automatically collect any information that could personally identify you. Personal information includes your name, street address, email address, billing information, credit card number and expiration date, and any other personally identifying information you may provide ("Personal Information"). Your Personal Information is only collected when you voluntarily submit it, for example, when you order products through the Earth Day Store, subscribe to our newsletter or email updates, participate in online interactive activities (such as chat rooms and bulletin boards), endorse our campaigns, sign up as a volunteer, list your event or group, make a donation, submit content or suggestions, or register for sweepstakes or contests. 

In addition to the ways described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy or at the time information is requested, we may use Personal Information received from visitors to our website for any of the following purposes: (1) to confirm, process and fulfill product orders; (2) to award prizes; (3) to respond to specific requests made by the visitor; (4) to demonstrate public support for policy proposals; (5) to provide to other environmental groups for use in collaborative educational and mobilizing efforts seeking to promote responsible environmental attitudes and policies; (6) to obtain parental consent for visitors under eighteen (18) years of age, when necessary; or (7) to protect the security or integrity of our website when necessary.

With the exceptions noted above, any Personal Information received from you will be retained by Earth Day Network and will not be sold, transferred or otherwise disclosed to any third party, unless such disclosure is required by law or court order.

****

**Technical Information and Traffic Data**

Each time you come to the Earth Day Network website, our web server (like most on the web) collects some basic technical information, including your IP address, your domain name, referral data (for example, the address of the last URL you were at before clicking through to our website) and browser and platform type ("Technical Information"). Earth Day Network may use this Technical Information to improve our website and make it more responsive to our visitors (see "Cookies" below). The Technical Information provided by our server is not linked to any of your Personal Information.

We also count, track, and aggregate your activity on the website into our analysis of general traffic flows at the site, allowing us to identify broad demographics about who uses the Earth Day Network website ("Traffic Data"). This Traffic Data is kept anonymously so that any such information does not personally identify you. We may share this Traffic Data with others. For example, we may report to third parties, such as the press, that a certain number of our volunteers come from a specific geographic area. 

****

**Cookies**

A "Cookie" is a short line of text stored on your computer by a website to differentiate between one anonymous visitor and another. For Grist Magazine and all parts of the Earth Day website other than the Earth Day Store, we only use Cookies for the limited purpose of counting the number of anonymous visitors to our site; we do not collect or store any personal information about you using Cookies.

In the Earth Day Store, we assign Cookies to shoppers for additional purposes, such as tracking the items in your shopping cart. Cookies help us recognize you as a prior customer and allow us to serve special features, which might be of interest to you. To better serve your needs, we will store your personal Earth Day Store online visiting preferences, but we will not store any Personal Information about you using Cookies technology. 

****

**How We Use Your Information**

Our website provides a variety of opportunities for your involvement with the Earth Day Network services and features. These opportunities and the ways in which your Personal Information is used, as expressly permitted by you upon your voluntary submission of such, are described below. 

****

**1\. Daily Grist**

To receive Daily Grist, you must submit your email address. Once signed up, you will start receiving summaries of environmental stories each weekday from the Earth Day Network's online environmental publication, _Grist Magazine_. We ask for your email addresses only to distribute Daily Grist; we do not share this information with anyone.

You can unsubscribe from Daily Grist by following the unsubscribe instructions found at the bottom of each email. 

****

**2\. Letters to the Editor of _Grist Magazine_**

To send a letter to the editor of _Grist Magazine_ , Earth Day Network's online publication, you agree to provide us with your phone number so that we can verify your identity should we choose to publish your letter. We do not keep this information for any other purpose, nor do we sell, trade, or otherwise disclose it to third parties. 

****

**3\. Sign Up for Earth Day News**

To receive Earth Day News emails, you must submit your email address, and you may be asked for your zip code if you live in the U.S. You will then start receiving email updates on a regular basis. We collect zip code information so that we can tell you about Earth Day events and happenings nearest to you, and we collect information about issues in which you are interested so that we can tailor updates to your concerns. You agree that we may share this Personal Information with our email list manager, a third party company that manages the list of subscribers to the Earth Day News emails for the sole purpose of sending you Earth Day News -- the email list manager cannot not sell your Personal Information or use it for any other purpose than described in this Privacy Policy.

You can unsubscribe from Earth Day News emails by following the unsubscribe instructions in each email or by visiting the Earth Day News sign-up page.

****

**4\. Endorse an Earth Day Campaign Agenda**

To endorse an Earth Day Campaign Agenda, you must provide us with your name and address. By choosing to endorse the Agenda, you agree that we may share your Personal Information with public officials and business leaders to demonstrate public support for our policy proposals. You also agree that we may aggregate this information to share anonymous data with the media, such as the number of endorsers, but we will not disclose your individual identity to the media without your express permission. Except for the ways described in this Privacy Policy, no other Personal Information will be shared with third parties when you endorse an agenda.

If your organization chooses to endorse any of Earth Day Network's Agendas, you must provide us with the organization's name, address, and other information about the group as described on the sign-up page. By choosing to endorse the Agenda, your organization agrees that we may share this information with public officials and business leaders to demonstrate public support for our policy proposals. Your organization also agrees that we may share this information with the media and that we may share the names and contact information of endorsing organizations with other organizations participating in Earth Day Network campaigns. Except for the ways described here, no other Personal Information about your organization will be shared with third parties. 

If you or your organization wishes to be removed as an endorser of any Earth Day Agenda, please email [earthday@earthday.net](mailto:earthday@earthday.net). 

****

**5\. List Your Group**

To list your group in our online directory, you must provide us with your organization's contact information and other details about the group as described on the List Your Group sign-up page. By registering, your organization agrees that we may publish your organization's Personal Information on our website and in the Worldwide Network Directory, but we will not publish names of individual contacts without the express permission of the individuals involved.

If your organization wishes to be removed from our website and the Worldwide Network Directory, please follow the removal instructions by visiting the List Your Group sign-up page or email [earthday@earthday.net](mailto:earthday@earthday.net). 

****

**6\. List Your Event**

To list your event, in our online events calendar, you must provide us with contact information, as well as a description of you and specifics about your events. By registering, you agree that we may publish this Personal Information on our website and in the events calendar, but will not publish names of individual contacts without the express permission of the individual involved. 

If you wish to have your event removed from our website and the events calendar, please follow the removal instructions by visiting the List Your Event sign-up page or email [earthday@earthday.net](mailto:earthday@earthday.net).

****

**8\. Earth Day Store**

If you wish to register with and/or purchase items from our online store, you agree to provide us with your name, address, email address, and credit card billing information. No orders will be accepted from persons under eighteen (18) years of age. Your Personal Information will only be collected on a voluntary basis for the purpose of fulfilling orders. By placing an order at the Earth Day Store, you agree that we may share this information with the third-party company directly involved in helping us complete the transaction and deliver the order. Your Personal Information will not be used for any other purpose by the third-party company contracted to fulfill online orders. Both the third-party company and Earth Day Network store your Personal Information so we can keep responsible records to handle your order, but we don't require it for you to obtain access to our store. Unless otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, your Personal Information will not be released to any other party nor will it be used to compile email lists. 

****

**9\. Donate**

To make a donation to Earth Day Network, you agree to submit your Personal Information so that we may collect it only for the purpose of processing donations. You also agree that we may store this information to keep responsible records. We do not share this information with anyone.

****

**10\. Send a Letter or Postcard**

To send a Letter or Postcard to an outside recipient, you must submit your name, address, and email address. You then agree that we may share your Personal Information with the recipient of the postcard/letter as listed on our website. We are not responsible for the use of your information once sent to the intended recipient. By sending a letter/postcard, you also agree that your information may be shared with other organizations supporting this environmental cause. We are not responsible for the use of your Personal Information by such organizations.

****

**11.Contests, Sweepstakes, and Giveaways**

To enter any of our contests, sweepstakes, or giveaways, you agree to provide the information requested. This information will be disclosed to third parties as required to process and fulfill the contest or sweepstake rules and to award prizes. Your Personal Information, however, will not be sold or used for other purposes unless described in this Privacy Policy or in the rules of the contest or sweepstakes posted on the website, or unless otherwise required by law.

****

**Other Disclosure of Personal Information**

Except for the circumstances described in this Privacy Policy, Earth Day Network will not otherwise use or disclose your Personal Information to third parties unless we are required to do so by law or we in good faith believe that such action is necessary to (1) comply with the law or legal process; (2) protect and defend our rights and property; (3) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of the Earth Day Network website; or (4) to protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public. 

****

**Security**

Earth Day Network uses all reasonable security safeguards to protect the information obtained against such risks as loss or unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification or disclosure by storing it on secure servers, which cannot be accessed over the Internet.

****

**Public Posting**

This policy does not protect information you may post to any online public forum within our website. 

****

**Unsubscribe and Data Removal Policies**

If you would like to unsubscribe from any of the Earth Day Network website services and features as described in this Privacy Policy, please follow the instructions within each listing or at the bottom of the emails you receive once signed up for the Earth Day Network service or feature. 

****

**Correction of Information**

Where necessary, you may correct or update any Personal Information that you have provided to us by following the instructions at the sign-up page for each of the services or features described above or by following the instructions listed on the emails you receive from us. 

****

**Other Sites**

Earth Day Network contains many links to other sites on the web. We cannot control and are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of these other websites. We encourage you to review the privacy policies for these websites before you submit any Personal Information.

****

**Your Consent**

By accessing and using our website, you consent to the collection and use of information as set forth in this Privacy Policy. If Earth Day Network revises its Privacy Policy, we will post the changes on our website. In the event you do not consent to these revisions, you may discontinue use of our website, or unsubscribe to our services or features. 

****

**Any Questions?**

If you have any further questions or concerns about Earth Day Network's Privacy Policy and use of Personal Information, please send them to [earthday@earthday.net](mailto:earthday@earthday.net).
